American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe. 1845-1865 APS.Archives.IIe APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe
1845-1865
APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - Letter to [George] Ord, January 3, 1845; 4"x4 7/8"; McEuen, Charles
    Scope and Contents note
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Has borrowed A.P.S. Transactions, n.s., VI.
  - Letter to the members of the American Philosophical Society, January 3, 1845; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Declines nomination to the presidency of the A.P.S. Enclosed in: Patterson to Franklin Bache, January 17, 1845.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, January 7, 1845; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Secretary of A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges his "election as one of the Vice Presidents of the American Philosophical Society."
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, January 13, 1845; 7 1/4" x 9"; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
    Librarian of A.P.S., Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. Returns volume of Penn's letters. Hopes to send "in due time the other two vols. of Hist. of U. S. and I hope a fourth."
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, January 17, 1845; 5" x 8"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning the election of new members to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, January 17, 1845; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and address. A.L.S Declines election as president of the A.P.S. See also, Patterson to members of the A.P.S., January 3, 1845.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 20, 1845; 10x8; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, A.L.S.: Cha[rle]s Hosmer. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 21, 1845; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Walter R. Johnson. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 25, 1845; 5" x 7 3/4"; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    [Philadelphia] 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests that books (not named) be delivered to bearer.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, January 27, 1845; 4 15/16" x 7 7/8"; Dillaway, Charles K. (Charles Knapp), 1804-1889
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Boston Society of Natural History forwards the missing numbers of its Journal to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to W. S. Young, Feb. 1, 1845; 6-1/2x4; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. George Ord will furnish coal. On same sheet is letter form W.S.Young to G. Ord; [Feb. 2, 1845].
  - Letter to George Ord, Feb. 2, 1845; 6-1/2x4; Young, William S.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Asks for coal. On same sheet as letter from Isaac Lea to W. S. Young; Feb. 1, 1845.
  - Letter to ----, February 4, 1845; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has signed and returned the diplomas (of membership in the A.P.S.).
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Feb. 8, 1845; 11x8-3/4; Hammer-Purgstall, Joseph, Frieherr von, 1774-1856
    Vienna, L.S. 1p.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., February 8, 1845; 7 7/8" x 10 1/16"; Hughes, John, 1797-1864
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsements. L. in 3d. per. Forwards package from Vienna to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, February 11, 1845; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Bache, Franklin, 1792-1864
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests that a special meeting of the A.P.S. be called for Friday evening next.
  - Letter to George Ord, February 11, 1845; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Librarian of A.P.S., Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires as to location of certain rare botanical works. "Captain Wilkes is now in Philadelphia... "
  - Committee of the Athenaeum to Franklin Bache, February 11, 1845; 8" x 10"; Athenaeum of Philadelphia
    [Philadelphia], 2pp. L.S.: T[homas] I.Wharton, and others. Proposal that the Athenaeum and A.P.S. erect a building "upon the present Lot for the accommodation of both Institutions." See Pro., IV, 142.
  - Letter to the [American] Philosophical Society, February 14, 1845; 7" x 8 3/4"; Lesueur, Charles Alexandre, 1778-1846
    Havre, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Presents to the A.P.S.: a copy of his Geological Views of the Falaises at the Cape of Laheve. See Pro., IV, 153. (For map see: 242.1.937:1843:L565vch.
  - Letter to ----, February 18, 1845; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; Angelis, Pedro de, 1784-1859
    Buenos Ayres, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Regarding an error in the title of a pamphlet by him. See Pro., IV, 161.
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, February 19, 1845; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; Ingersoll, Joseph Reed, 1786-1868
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses letter from the French minister explaining gift of books from the Minister of War to the A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on proposal of Athenaeum to erect building for the joint use of the two societies, Feb. 21, 1845; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R.M. Patterson, G.Ord, Isaac Lea, Geo. W. Smith and Geo. M. Justice. 2p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 146.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, February 21, 1845; 5 5/16" x 9"; Seldener, Richard
    President of the [American] Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Transmits to the A.P.S.: a package of books from M. Berzelius of Stockholm. See Pro., IV, 143.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 22, 1845; 9-1/2x7-3/4; American Colonization Society
    Washington, L.S.: W.McLain. 1p.,end. Thanks for Transactions. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, February 27, 1845; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will be impossible for him to meet committee this afternoon.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, February 28, 1845; 8 15/16" x 10 11/16"; Seldener, Richard
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will forward package for Royal Society of Sciences of Upsal, by way of New York, when opportunity offers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb., 1845; 9-3/4x8; Bowditch Library
    Boston, A.L.S.: H.I.Bowditch. 1p.,end.: A.L. Elwyn and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, March 3, 1845; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Haldeman, Samuel Steman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Natural History Society of Bern, Switzerland, desires to exchange its Denkschriften for the Transactions of American scientific societies.
  - Report of committee on paper by [S. S.] Haldeman on the "Coleoptera longicorna of the United States", March 7, 1845; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: T. R. Peale, Isaac Lea, and G. Ord. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 49. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., X, 27-66.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 9, 1845; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Dillaway, Charles K. (Charles Knapp), 1804-1889
    Librarian of A.P.S., Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The librarian of the Boston Society of Natural History requests A.P.S. Transactions, n.s., I, III, V, and Proceedings, nos. 21 and 24.
  - Letter to George Ord, Librarian of A.P.S., March 14, 1845; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    London, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Suggests that Charles L. Bonaparte be authorized to represent the A.P.S. at meeting of the Italian Scientific Association at Naples in October. See Pro., Iv, 153-154 Printed: APS Proceedings, Vol.90, No.5,December,1946.
  - Letter to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 19, 1845; 10-1/4x8; Muséum national d'historie naturelle (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E.Chevreul and Jussieu. 1p.,end.: A.L.Elwyn. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to George Ord, March 23, 1845; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Dillaway, Charles K. (Charles Knapp), 1804-1889
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Boston Society of Natural History sends to the A.P.S.: pp. 129-200 of Proceedings, and Journal, V, no. 1.
  - Letter to George Ord, April 11, 1845; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Librarian of A.P.S., Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement A.L.S. Requests two copies of Proceedings of A.P.S. centennial.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 18, 1845; 10x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: John J. Bennett. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher] and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, April 18, 1845; 8" x 10"; Sartori, John B.
    Librarian of A.P.S., Leghorn, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. (Duplicate.) Offers to sell his secret of fixation of mercury to the A.P.S. Enclosed in Sartori to Ord, April 29, 1845.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society Philadelphia, April 19, 1845; 9x7; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: R.Clarke. 1p.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, April 22, 1845; 4 7/8" x 7 5/8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.N.S. Requests a complete set of A.P.S. Transactions, old series, as he can sell the same.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, April 29, 1845; 8" x 10"; Sartori, John B.
    Librarian of A.P.S., Leghorn, 1p. and endorsement. L.S. By brig Aldebaran sends piece of fiexed mercury to Mr. Ord, to be shown to the A.P.S. See Pro., IV, 184.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, April 30, 1845; 7 3/8" x 9"; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., R[oya]l College of Surgeons, [London], 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of diploma of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 1, 1845; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: P.Vaughan, Esq. Thanks for publications.
  - Receipt to the American Philosophical society for hospital expenses ofr Augustus Larrentree, May 5, 1845; 4x7-1/2; Pennsylvania Hospital. Contributors to
    D.S.: Wm. G. Malin. 1p.,end.and end. Paid by George ord.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 22, 1845; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Dillaway, Charles K. (Charles Knapp), 1804-1889
    Librarian of A.P.S., Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The librarian of the Boston Society of Natural History requests a copy of the Catalogue of the Library of the A.P.S., published in 1824.
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society, May 23, 1845; 5-1/2x7; Law Academy of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Edward Armstrong. 1p., and end. Receipt for portrait of DuPonceau, "allowed to be copied for the use of the Law Academy of Philadelphia."
  - Letter to George Ord, May 23, 1845; 5" x 8"; Wilkes, Charles, 1798-1877
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents copy of his Narrative of the Exploring Expedition to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 28, 1845; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Brown, David Paul, 1795-1872
    Secretary of the A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is disposed to become tenant of office below Athenaeum at $150 per year. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, May 29, 1845; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
    Librarian of the A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns designated books to the A.P.S. Will present a copy of his essay for the Ethnological Association of New York as soon as it appears.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 30, 1845; 7 13/16" x 9 15/16"; Delafield, Richard, 1798-1873
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Military Academy, West Point, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Superintendent of the Military Academy requests information as to subscription to Astronomische Nachrichten.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 30, 1845; 5" x 8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents a copy of Etudes sur les Échinides, by Charles des Moulins. Also some reports and a catalogue of birds. See Pro., IV, 172.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 31, 1845; 8" x 10"; Beck, Theodoric Romeyn, 1791-1855
    Albany, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The secretary of the New York State Library submits a list of A.P.S. publications in their possession, with request that deficiencies be filled, if possible.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 31, 1845; 5" x 7 7/8"; Brown, David Paul, 1795-1872
    Librarian of the A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has requested Mr. John Haviland to examine room below Athenaeum to determine the need of repairs.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May, 1845; 9-3/4x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Ogilby. 1p.,end. Thanks for the Proceedings.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, June 4, 1845; 4 7/8" x 6 1/2"; Brown, David Paul, 1795-1872
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Has decided not to rent room under the Athenaeum, but to take an office elsewhere. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 4, 1845; 10x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John J. Bennett. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 4, 1845; 9x7-1/2; Royal Astronomical Society
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: R.Harris. 1p.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, Philadelphia, June 6, 1845; 10x8; New York State Library
    Albany, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Isaac Lea to George Ord, June 11, 1845; 5" x 8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests balance due the Publications committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 14, 1845; 10x8-1/2; Zantedeschi, Francesco, 1797-1873
    Venice, A.L.S. 1p.and end. In Italian. Presents five scientific works to the society (listed in letter).
  - Letter to J.K. Kane, June 17, 1845; 10x8; Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Francis Whishaw. 1p.,end.: R.D[unglison]. Thanks for publications of APS.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 24, 1845; 4 15/16" x 7 3/4"; Du Bois, William E. (William Ewing), 1810-1881
    U. S. Mint, [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to borrow [William] Marsden, Numismata orientalia illustrata.
  - Statement of account with the American philosophical society, June 25, 1845; 11x8; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Paris, D. 1p.and end. In French.
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society], June 28, 1845; 8" x 9"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsements. Pr.D. Treasury department directs map of New York bay and harbor to be sent to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June, 1845; 10x7-1/2; New-York Historical Society
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: George Gibbs. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, Philadelphia, June, 1845; 10x8
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: S.Hunter Christie. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for publication on DuPonceau.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June, 1845; 10x8; Royal Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: S.Hunter Christie. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Proceedings of the academy of natural sciences.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, July 1, 1845; 8 3/8" x 10 7/8"; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Acknowledges receipt of several letters. Book news.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, July 7, 1845; 6 1/2" x 8"; Barclay, James J., 1794-1885
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endrosement. Wishes to purchase A.P.S. Transactions, I, III, and XIII.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 7, 1845; 6 3/8" x 8 1/8"; Eichthal, Gustave d', 1804-1886
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Presents to the A.P.S.: Etudes sur l'histoire primitive des races Océaniennes et Américaines.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., July 12, 1845; 8" x 9"; Bonaparte, Charles Lucian, 1803-1857
    Rome, 1 p. and endorsement. Unsigned extract of L. Returns thanks for having been chosen as the representative of the A.P.S. at the Seventh Congress of the Italian Association, to be held at Naples in September next. Printed: APS Proceedings, Vol.90, no.5 December,1946.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, July 15, 1845; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Introducing Mr. [Richard S.] McCulloh, who wishes to consult certain books in the library of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, July 16, 1845; 4 1/8" x 7 7/8"; Carey, Henry Charles, 1793-1879
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Borrowed [Samuel] Kidd's work on China, which he has passed on to [Horace] Binney.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 4, 1845; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Short, Charles Wilkins, 1794-1863
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Fernbank,Ohio, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents a few botanical catalogues of his friend, Dr. Chapman, of Florida. Introduces his son and Mr. Richardson.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 25, 1845; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Loomis, Elias, 1811-1889
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement A.L.S. Requests Mr. Ord to order nos. 527 and 528 of the Astronomische Nachrichten for him.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 11, 1845; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Renard. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, September 12, 1845; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Beck, Theodoric Romeyn, 1791-1855
    Albany, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Lists various publications of the A.P.S. in which the New York State Library is deficient. Hopes to complete files. See Pro., IV, 190.
  - Report of committee on a paper by William McIlvaine, "A perpetual calendar, civil and ecclesiastical", Sept. 19, 1845; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R. M. Patterson, John F. Frazer, and Sears C. Walker. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 192-197. Printed: APS Trans.,n.s.,X,103-129.
  - Report of the committee on the claim of the executors of Mr. Nathan Dunn, Sept. 19, 1845; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Clement C. Biddle, H. J. Williams, J. K, Kane, J. J. Vanderkemp. 3p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 196.
  - Letter to George Ord, September 24, 1845; 5" x 8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests use of room for Wistar Party on Friday evening next.
  - Letter to I[saac] Lea, Oct. 3, 1845; 5x8; Young, William S.
    Philadelphia, L.S.by W.H. Fox. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the delivery of coal.
  - Letter to Isaac Lea, Oct. 4, 1845; 3x8; Young, William S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning the delivery of coal.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 14, 1845; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Beck, Theodoric Romeyn, 1791-1855
    Albany, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The secretary of the New York State Library acknowledges the receipt of certain numbers of A.P.S. Proceedings. See Pro., IV, 198.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, October 16, 1845; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Markoe, Francis, 1801-1871
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Is holding some volumes from St. Petersburg (not named) for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Alfred L. Elwyn, October 17, 1845; 7 7/8" X 10"; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Hopes to have obituary notice of the late [William H.] Keating ready in the course of November. See Pro., IV, 203.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, October 21, 1845; 4 1/4" x 6 3/4"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Boston, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has received package from London containing magnetic observations at Toronto, and The Magnetic Observatory at Philadelphia, for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 30, 1845; 4" x 5 1/8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether Mr. Ord has come upon a copper plate of insects amon [John] Vaughan's effects.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, November 1, 1845; 8 3/8" x 10 5/8"; Sartori, John B.
    2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Concerning the fixation of mercury. Regrets lack of interest on part of A.P.S. This my force him to sell secret to one of the European scientific societies. See Pro., IV, 226.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 1, 1845; 11x8-3/4; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, Printed L.filled in ms.S.: Svedborn. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for publications and forwards their publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., November 3, 1845; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Totten, Joseph Gilbert, 1788-1864
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Papers on Practical Engineering, no. 3.
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society for ground rent taxes, Nov. 6, 1845; 7x8; Graff, Charles
    Philadelphia, D. 1p.,end.by [George Ord],and end.
  - Report of committee for revising the laws, Nov. 7, 1845; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: G.Ord, R.M. Patterson, and W.H. Dillingham. 1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 210.
  - Report of committee on a paper by Major James D. Graham, "Observations for the magnetic dip...in 1840;", Nov. 7, 1845; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], D.S.: Sears C. Walker, R.M. Patterson, and John F. Frazer. 1p., end. See APS Proc., IV, 205-207. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., IX, 329-345.
  - Treatise on the parallactic eyepieces, November 15, 1845
  - Letter to George Ord, November 16, 1845; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests that parcel from [Stephen] Alexander be sent to [Eugenius] Nulty. Death of [D. B.] Warden.
  - Statement of the value of marks, made to Robert Orr, November 17, 1845; 12-1/2x8, 3x8; Lang, John C.
    A.D.S. 2p.and add.,end.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 24, 1845; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Alexander, Stephen, 1806-1883
    Librarian of A.P.S., Princeton, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Note of apology for delay in returning books to the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 25, 1845; 7-1/4x4-1/4; Cooke, John
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.,end.and add. Forwards pamphlets from Upsala.
  - Letter to [Robley] Dunglison, December 3, 1845; 8" x 10"; Abert, John James, 1788-1863
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter. Will write to Baltimore and endeavor to get [J. N.] Nicollet's Journal of his life. FILM403 FRAME 47
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, Dec. 3, 1845; 8" x 9 7/8"; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891